An angel falls. A warrior rises.
Alita: Battle Angel is a action, science fiction,
adventure film directed by Robert Rodriguez.
When Alita awakens with no memory of who she is in a future world she does not recognize, she is taken in by Ido, a compassionate doctor who
realizes that somewhere in this abandoned cyborg shell is the heart and soul of a young woman with an extraordinary past.
Alita, played by Rosa Salazar.
Dr. Dyson Ido, played by Christoph Waltz.
Chiren, played by Jennifer Connelly.
Vector, played by Mahershala Ali.
Zapan, played by Ed Skrein.
Grewishka, played by Jackie Earle Haley.
Alita: Battle Angel is a 2019 American cyberpunk action film based
on Yukito Kishiro's manga series Battle Angel Alita.
It was directed by Robert Rodriguez, produced by James Cameron and Jon
Landau, and written by Cameron and Laeta Kalogridis.
Using motion-capture and CGI animation, Rosa Salazar stars as Alita, a cyborg who awakens in
a new body without memory of her past and sets out to uncover her destiny.
Many of the supporting roles, played by Christoph Waltz, Jennifer Connelly, Mahershala
Ali, Ed Skrein, Jackie Earle Haley and Keean Johnson, used live-actors.
Announced in 2003, production was repeatedly delayed due to
Cameron's work on Avatar (2009) and its sequels.
After years of development hell, Rodriguez was announced as Alita's director in
April 2016, with Salazar cast as the lead the following month.
Principal photography began in October 2016 in Austin, Texas, mostly at
Rodriguez's Troublemaker Studios, and lasted until February 2017.
Alita: Battle Angel had its world premiere at the Odeon Leicester Square in London on January 31,
2019, and was released in the United States on February 14, by 20th Century Fox.
The film grossed $405 million, making it Rodriguez's
highest-grossing film, and received mixed reviews from critics.
In the years since its release, the film has garnered a cult following.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of martial arts, bounty
hunter, dystopia, extreme sports, superhero.
The tone is thought_provoking.